Guide to the Houston Assembly of Delphian Chapters Records
University of Houston Libraries
Houston Assembly of Delphian Chapters Records
1925
02/2008-011
Houston Assembly of Delphian Chapters
5.00 linear feet
Special Collections, University of Houston Libraries
The collection is housed in 5 boxes and organized in 10 series: Organizational Information; The Delphian Society Manuals; Special Projects; Correspondence; Bit-O-News Newsletters; Photographic Material; Publicity Clippings; Delphian Memorial Scholarship Fund; Delphian Chapters’ Scrapbooks and Houston Delphian Assembly Scrapbooks. These series document the organization’s operations, numerous social events and scholarship fund information.
Historical Note:
The Houston Assembly of Delphian Chapters is an organization for women, which has three-fold purpose. It is dedicated to intellectual enrichment, social enhancement, and philanthropic endeavors. Founded in Houston in 1924, it is one of the oldest clubs for women in the greater metropolitan area. The organization has continued uninterrupted through wars, recessions, and most importantly, the changing role of women in society.
The organization is known for hosting a wide range of social functions, including an annual gala, luncheons, style shows, cultural events, and tours. The proceeds fund scholarships to area undergraduate students at the University of Houston. In addition, Delphian chapters meet in small discussion groups guided by seminar material focused on specific topics. Such a meeting structure illustrates the importance placed on enriching intellect by the Houston Assembly of Delphian Chapters.
Access Terms
This Collection is indexed under the following controlled access subject terms.
Corporate Name:
Houston Assembly of Delphian Chapters
Genre/Form of Material:
Clippings (information artifacts); Newsletters; Photographs; Records (documents); Scrapbooks
Topical Term:
Nonprofit organizations -- Texas -- Houston; Women -- Societies and clubs -- Texas -- Houston
Conditions Governing Access:
Open for research.
Acquisition Information
Information of acquisition method not available.
Scope and Contents
The collection is housed in 5 boxes and organized in 10 series: Organizational Information; The Delphian Society Manuals; Special Projects; Correspondence; Bit-O-News Newsletters; Photographic Material; Publicity Clippings; Delphian Memorial Scholarship Fund; Delphian Chapters’ Scrapbooks and Houston Delphian Assembly Scrapbooks. These series document the organization’s operations, numerous social events and scholarship fund information.
Detailed List of Contents
- Organizational Information, id72680
  - Houston Delphian Assembly (Record Book), 1929-1933; id72700 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Houston Delphian Assembly (Binder), 1933-1937; id72701 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Houston Delphian Assembly (Binder), 1952-1955; id72702 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Alpha Zeta Chapter (Binder), 1978-1996; id72703 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Delphian (Binder), 1981; id72704 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Beta Sigma Chapter (Binder), 1984-1992; id72705 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Executive Board / Committee (2 Binders with duplicate information), 1988-1989; id91877 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Volunteer Hours, 1990-1991; id91878 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Houston Assembly of Delphian Chapters, Inc (Binder), 1992; id91879 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Miscellaneous, id91880 (Box 2, Folder 4)
- The Delphian Society Manuals, id72681
  - Leader’s Manual for Delphian Chapters, 1925; id91881 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Delphian in Brief, 1951; id91882 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Delphian Seminar Programs on Patterns for Modern Living, 1964-1966; id91883 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Compendium, 1966; id91884 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - The Delphian Handbook, id91885 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - The Delphian Society, n.d; id91886 (Box 2, Folder 10)
- Special Projects, id72683
  - The Address of Leon Jaworski to the Houston Assembly Chapters, 1968; id91887 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - "Australia - The Romantic Adventure” Gala (Binder), 1988-1989; id91888 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - “A Night at the Monte Carlo” Gala (Binder), 1998-1999; id91889 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - 75th Annual Diamond Anniversary Gala, 2000; id91890 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - “Stars at Night” Delphian Variety Talent Show (Binder), 2001-2002; id91891 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - “Stars at Night” Delphian Variety Talent Show Video Tapes (Part 1 and Part 2), 2001-2002; id91892 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Cookbooks, 1976, 1983, 2005; id91893 (Box 3, Folder 7)
- Correspondence, id72684
  - 1935-1939, id91894 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - 1940-1946, id91895 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - 1953-1958, id91896 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - 1982-1991, id91897 (Box 4, Folder 4)
- Bit-O-News Newsletters, id72685
  - Article Typescripts, 1969-1979; id91898 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Article Typescripts, 1980-1989; id91899 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - 1960-1962, id91900 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - 1963-1965, id91901 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - 1966-1968, id91902 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - 1969-1971, id91903 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - 1972-1974, id91904 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - 1975-1977, id91905 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - 1978-1980, id91906 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - 1981-1983, id91907 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - 1984-1986, id91908 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - 1987-1988, 1991-1993, id91909 (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - 1994-1995, 1997-1999, 2002-2005, id91910 (Box 4, Folder 17)
- Photographic Material, id72686
  - Prints, 1926-1930; id91911 (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Prints, 1957-1959; id91912 (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Prints, 1960-1963; id91913 (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - Prints, 1964-1969; id91914 (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - Prints, 1970-1979; id91915 (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - Prints, 1980-1990; id91916 (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - Prints, 1992; id91917 (Box 4, Folder 24)
  - Prints, 1993; id91918 (Box 4, Folder 25)
  - Prints, 2001 -2002; id91919 (Box 4, Folder 26)
  - Prints, Houston Assembly Officers, n.d.; id91920 (Box 4, Folder 27)
  - Prints, Houston Assembly Presidents, 1955-1959; id91921 (Box 4, Folder 28)
  - Prints, Houston Assembly Presidents, 1960-1970; id91922 (Box 4, Folder 29)
  - Prints, Houston Assembly Presidents, 1970-1978; id91923 (Box 4, Folder 30)
  - Prints, Houston Assembly Presidents, 1981-1985; id91924 (Box 4, Folder 31)
  - Prints, University of Houston Exhibits of Delphian Contributions, 1960’s; id91925 (Box 4, Folder 32)
  - 5 small boxes of slides, id91926 (Box 4, Folder 33)
  - Negatives, 1996; id91928 (Ovs box 5, Item 1)
  - Collages, 2004; id91929 (Ovs box 5, Item 2)
- Publicity Clippings, id72687
  - 1955-1959, id91930 (Box 4, Folder 34)
  - 1960-1962, id91931 (Box 4, Folder 35)
  - 1963, id91932 (Box 4, Folder 36)
  - 1964, id91933 (Box 4, Folder 37)
  - 1965, id91934 (Box 4, Folder 38)
  - 1966, id91935 (Box 4, Folder 39)
  - 1967, id91936 (Box 4, Folder 40)
  - 1968-1969, id91937 (Box 4, Folder 41)
  - 1970-1971, id91938 (Box 4, Folder 42)
  - 1972-1976, id91939 (Box 4, Folder 43)
  - 1977-1986, id91940 (Box 4, Folder 44)
  - Pubic Relations Information, id91941 (Box 4, Folder 45)
- Delphian Memorial Scholarship Fund, id72688
  - Financial Records, id91942 (Box 4, Folder 46)
  - Miscellaneous Records, id91943 (Box 4, Folder 47)
  - Book of Memorial Donations (1965-1998), id91944 (Ovs box 5, Item 3)
- Delphian Chapters' Scrapbooks, id72682
  - Beta Nu Chapter, 1982-1993; id91945 (Ovs box 5, Item 4)
  - Beta Nu Chapter, 1982-1993; id91946 (Ovs box 5, Item 5)
- Houston Delphian Assembly Scrapbooks, id91875
  Scope and Contents
  Stacked on shelves-- Not Boxed
  - History Book I, 1937-1952; id91947 (Item 1)
  - History Book II, 1952-1956; id91948 (Item 2)
  - 1959-1963, id91949 (Item 3)
  - 1963-1965, id91950 (Item 4)
  - 1965-1967, id91951 (Item 5)
  - 1967-1969, id91952 (Item 6)
  - 1969-1971, id91953 (Item 7)
  - 1971-1974, id91954 (Item 8)
  - 1977-1980, id91955 (Item 9)
  - 1980-1983, id91956 (Item 10)
  - 1983-1986, id91957 (Item 11)
  - 1985-1988, id91958 (Item 12)
  - 1988-1991, id91959 (Item 13)
- Other Delphian Scrapbooks, id117838
  - Delphian Past Presidents Club of Houston, 1980-81; id117839 (Item 1)
- Houston Assembly of Delphian Chapters, 2015 Accession, id163590
  Accrual of additional unprocessed materials acquired on April 28, 2015.